I right hand fail.
Prawa ręka zawiodła.
A dog, huh?
Pies?
I suppose it's partially due to its maturation environment,
Dojrzewał w takim środowisku i nie przyłożył się do nauki.
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI (PUBLISHER: KODANSHA "AFTERNOON")
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
DEMON IN THE FLESH
DEMON W CIELE
Hey, hey. Are you a college student?
Hej. Jesteś studentką?
Oh, you're not? An office worker?
Nie? Pracujesz w biurze?
Seriously?
Serio?
No way.
Nie wierzę.
You're super hot.
Jesteś seksowna.
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
Hey, wait a second. What's wrong with a little fun?
Stój. Zabawmy się, to nic złego.
Yeah, come have fun with us. Just for a bit.
Zabaw się z nami. Tylko chwilę.
Come on, yeah?
Chodź.
I'll walk you home.
Odprowadzę cię.
You've got some guts to do that to us!
Masz jaja, żeby tak nas traktować!
I don't think my stomach can hold four at once.
Mój żołądek nie strawi czterech osób na raz.
Four?
Czterech?
I overdid it and took two swings.
Przesadziłem i zrobiłem dwa zamachy.
I suppose I should change my face just to be safe.
Lepiej zmienię twarz.
You don't feel the need to go to the police anymore?
Już nie chcesz iść na policję?
Yeah.
Nie.
Without you, I'd be an easy kill
Bez ciebie będę łatwym celem
for those creepy parasitic creatures.
dla tych pasożytniczych stworów.
A wise decision.
Słuszna decyzja.
Hey, I want to have a name to call you.
Chcę cię jakoś nazywać.
I don't.
Nie mam imienia. Nie jestem człowiekiem ani zwierzęciem.
But I can't just keep calling you "you" or "him".
Muszę cię jakoś nazywać.
Then call me Migi.
Mów na mnie „Migi”.
What? "Migi"?
Co? „Migi”?
Yes.
Tak.
I grew by eating your right hand,
Zjadłem twoją rękę, więc jestem „Migi”.
You can be pretty simple-minded sometimes.
Lubisz prostotę.
I simply lack interest in the concept of names.
Nie obchodzą mnie imiona.
Nice shot!
- Dobry rzut! - Izumi-kun jest niezły.
What?
Co?
I guess.
Chyba tak.
Izumi-kun!
Izumi-kun!
Satomi says she'll forgive you
Satomi mówi, że ci wybaczy, jeśli znowu trafisz do kosza!
Hey, Yuko!
Yuko!
What's with Nagai?
Co go ugryzło?
NAGAI
NAGAI
Five more seconds!
Jeszcze pięć sekund!
Here goes nothing!
Raz kozie śmierć!
Yeah!
Tak!
Thank you, Migi.
Dziękuję, Migi.
That was amazing, huh, Satomi?
To było ekstra. Prawda, Satomi?
Yeah.
Tak.
Damn Izumi.
Przeklęty Izumi.
Okay, I'll go on ahead.
To ja was zostawię.
I'm sorry!
Przepraszam!
I wasn't trying to touch you when I did.
Nie chciałem tego zrobić.
My right hand just moved and…
Moja ręka się ruszyła i…
I'm really sorry!
Bardzo przepraszam!
Are you truly sorry?
Naprawdę ci przykro?
I am!
Tak!
I seriously am!
Naprawdę!
Maybe I can forgive you if you'll treat me to some pancakes next Sunday.
Wybaczę ci, jeśli w niedzielę zabierzesz mnie na naleśniki.
If you do it again, though, you're toast.
Ale zrób to jeszcze raz, a będzie po tobie.
I'll never do it again! I promise!
Więcej tego nie zrobię! Obiecuję!
All right.
Dobrze.
It's a promise, then.
Obiecałeś.
It's nothing!
Nic się nie stało!
I'm fine!
Wszystko w porządku!
-Izumi-kun. -Oh?
- Izumi-kun. - Tak?
You are Izumi Shinichi-kun, right?
Jesteś Izumi Shinichi-kun, prawda?
What are you talking about?
O czym ty mówisz?
Of course I am.
Jasne, że to ja.
Later.
Do zobaczenia.
What the hell was that about?
Co to było?
I was curious about human mating behavior.
Ciekawią mnie stosunki płciowe ludzi.
You wanted to mate with that female, didn't you?
Chciałeś z nią odbyć stosunek, prawda?
What?
Co?
Mate?
Stosunek?
It's not like that!
- To nie tak! - Izumi!
Come with me.
Chodź ze mną.
So, were you talking to yourself to practice pick-up lines? Huh?
Gadałeś do siebie, żeby ćwiczyć teksty na podryw?
Not really.
Nie.
I have to change out of my gym clothes.
Muszę się przebrać.
Hold it!
Czekaj!
You know I like Murano, don't you?
Wiesz, że podoba mi się Murano?
Oh, you do?
Naprawdę?
Fight me.
Walcz ze mną.
Huh?
Co?
Come on. Give me a break.
Nie żartuj.
Why did you do that?
Dlaczego to zrobiłeś?
What's the matter?
Co jest?
Can't fight back?
Nie oddasz mi?
If Migi goes all-out like before,
Jeśli Migi zaatakuje jak wcześniej,
this guy might get seriously hurt.
to chłopak nieźle oberwie.
Bastard!
Draniu!
You weakling!
Ty słabeuszu!
Don't.
Nie rób tego.
Learn to hold back a little, idiot.
Panuj nad sobą, idioto.
"Idiot"?
„Idioto”?
That's something you call someone who is less intelligent than you.
Mówi się tak na osoby, które są od nas głupsze.
You'd better not have killed him.
Obyś go nie zabił.
Don't worry.
Spokojnie.
By the way, Shinichi.
Swoją drogą, Shinichi.
It is not good for your health to suppress your excretory functions.
Tłumienie funkcji wydalniczych szkodzi zdrowiu.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
What?
Co?
I told you not to talk to me when people are around.
Miałeś milczeć przy ludziach.
Let me try to cause an erection in this sex organ.
Spróbuję wywołać erekcję tego narządu płciowego.
What did you say?
Co takiego?
Hey! What are you doing?
Hej! Co robisz?
No! Stop it!
Nie! Przestań!
It's cold, Shinichi.
Zimno mi.
Shut up.
Zamknij się.
If you don't keep yourself clean,
Jeśli nie będziesz się mył, rozwiną się grzyby i będzie swędziało…
Shut up!
Cicho!
Why are you talking to your Johnson?
Dlaczego rozmawiasz ze swoją fujarką?
The Mincemeat Murders?
Morderstwa zmielonego mięsa?
Yeah.
Tak.
Cases of people being torn to pieces are happening
W wielu miejscach na świecie znajdowane są ludzkie szczątki.
There are pretty graphic videos being upped to the net, too.
W Internecie jest dużo drastycznych filmików.
What about the killer?
A morderca?
They haven't caught him yet.
Jeszcze go nie złapali.
More like, no one person can tear up several people at the same time
I jedna osoba nie poćwiartuje tylu osób w tym samym czasie,
so I bet it's not just one killer
więc to nie jest jedna osoba, tylko jakaś sekta.
Come to think of it, your brother's a detective, right?
Twój brat jest detektywem, prawda?
Yeah, but he won't tell me anything about these murders.
Tak, ale nic mi nie powie o tych morderstwach.
If you think about it, wouldn't that mean
Czy to znaczy,
the cops and the government are already doing something about it?
że policja i władze zajmują się tą sprawą?
So, are they more of "yours", Migi?
Czyli jest więcej takich jak ty?
MORE "MINCEMEAT MURDERS" NATIONWIDE
MORDERSTWA W CAŁYM KRAJU
That is certain.
Na pewno.
I learned from observing the dog the other day
Obserwowałem tamtego psa i wiem,
that those with dogs as hosts only eat dogs.
że mieszkający w psach jedzą tylko psy.
Those with humans as hosts eat humans.
Mieszkający w ludziach jedzą ludzi.
We therefore specialize in cannibalism.
Jesteśmy kanibalami.
What are you thinking?
O czym myślisz?
Should we really stay silent about this?
Czy nie powinniśmy o tym powiedzieć.
What do you mean by "should we stay silent"?
„Czy nie powinniśmy o tym powiedzieć”?
We can't just let them be.
Nie możemy tego tak zostawić.
They're killing people in droves.
Zabijają ludzi.
What do you mean by "let them be"?
Jak to „zostawić”?
Listen!
Słuchaj!
Only we know their true nature.
Tylko my wiemy, czym są.
There will only be more victims if we don't do something.
Jeśli nic nie zrobimy, będzie więcej ofiar.
That's why…
Dlatego…
That's why what?
Dlatego co?
If I tell the world about you and have them research you…
Jeśli o tobie powiem i cię zbadają…
What are you saying?
O czym ty mówisz?
I do not understand your logic.
Nie rozumiem cię.
My kind is simply eating.
Mój gatunek tylko zjada.
It's natural for life forms to eat.
Wszystkie formy życia jedzą.
Is it so unpleasant to you that your kind are being eaten?
Przykro ci, że zjadamy twój gatunek?
Of course it is!
Oczywiście, że tak!
Human life is precious, isn't it?
Życie ludzkie jest cenne.
I don't understand.
Nie rozumiem.
I only value my own life.
Ja cenię tylko swoje życie.
I have never considered the life of any other being valuable.
Nigdy nie myślałem, że życie innych ma jakąś wartość.
I'm sure.
Nie wątpię.
You are an animal. An insect.
Jesteś zwierzęciem, robakiem.
Is that your attempt to be disdainful?
Próbujesz mi ubliżyć?
If you were to take actions that would harm me,
Jeśli chciałbyś mnie skrzywdzić,
I would do everything in my power to prevent them.
zrobiłbym wszystko, żebyś tego nie zrobił.
Oh?
Serio?
Can you survive if you oppose me?
Przeżyjesz beze mnie?
You're just a parasite.
Jesteś pasożytem.
I will protect your life, of course,
Będę cię bronić, to oczywiste,
but I am more than capable of making you incapable of speech.
ale mogę sprawić, że nie będziesz mógł mówić.
I can also rob you of your sight and hearing.
Mogę cię też pozbawić wzroku i słuchu.
What?
Co?
You should rest a while.
Odpocznij sobie.
Demon.
Demon.
Shinichi, upon researching the concept of demons,
Shinichi, poczytałem trochę o demonach
I believe that among all life, humans are the closest thing to it.
i uważam, że ze wszystkich form życia ludziom do nich najbliżej.
Although humans kill and eat a wide variety of life forms,
Ludzie zabijają i jedzą wiele gatunków,
my kind eats merely one or two kinds at most.
a mój zjada tylko jeden czy dwa.
We are quite frugal in comparison.
Jesteśmy oszczędne.
I don't even want to hear that kind of logic.
Nie chcę słuchać takich rzeczy.
People are being killed.
Ludzie są mordowani.
I'm the only one who knows what the killers really are.
Tylko ja wiem, kim są mordercy.
We're mincemeat.
Jesteśmy mięsem.
"MINCEMEAT MURDERS"
„MORDERSTWA ZMIELONEGO MIĘSA”
Foolish humans. Why act so surprised when you turn cows and pigs into mincemeat
Głupi ludzie. Dlaczego są tacy zaskoczeni?
Well, now. How rare.
A to nowość.
He is one of my kind.
Jest jednym z nas.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
-One's approaching. -Huh?
Jeden się zbliża.
One of my kind.
Jeden z moich.
It's somewhere among the crowd to our left.
Jest gdzieś w tłumie po lewej.
I am certain of it, although there are too many people for me
Jestem tego pewien, ale jest tu zbyt dużo ludzi,
to identify the individual.
żebym go rozpoznał.
We should distance ourselves.
Chodźmy stąd.
One misstep and we will have to fight to the death yet again.
Jedna pomyłka i będziemy musieli walczyć o życie.
Pick up the pace.
Szybciej.
It's coming closer.
Zbliża się.
Maybe it wants to invite us to join Cannibals Anonymous?
Może chce nas zaprosić do Klubu Kanibali?
Shinichi, where do you think you're going?
Shinichi, dokąd idziesz?
It is approximately 40 meters away, immediately behind you.
Jest 40 metrów za nami.
I want to meet this murderer face-to-face.
Chcę się z nim spotkać twarzą w twarz.
Don't be an idiot.
Nie bądź głupi.
You'll get yourself killed.
Zginiesz.
Then you should protect me.
No to mnie chroń.
I doubt it will play out the same way it did with the dog last time.
Wątpię, że pójdzie tak samo jak z psem.
No one will see us here, right?
Nikt nas tu nie zobaczy?
I find the human psyche difficult to comprehend.
Nie rozumiem ludzkiej psychiki.
Right now, you seem numb to fear.
Teraz się nie boisz.
Why?
Dlaczego?
Many people have been killed.
Zginęło wiele osób.
If I don't do something, even Murano might be…
Jeśli nic nie zrobię, nawet Murano może…
You're telling me I should just stand by and watch,
Czyli mam siedzieć bezczynnie,
even if I know who's killing people?
mimo że wiem, kto zabija ludzi?
I'm going to fight for humanity!
Będę walczył o ludzkość!
For humanity. I see.
„O ludzkość”. Rozumiem.
And I need your help to do that!
A ty musisz mi pomóc!
Help me.
Pomóż mi.
Come on, Migi!
Proszę, Migi!
Five more meters.
Pięć metrów.
I see.
Już rozumiem.
So that is why you ran.
Dlatego uciekałeś.
This human's brain survived, wholly intact.
Ludzki mózg przeżył nienaruszony.
He is certainly a danger.
On stanowi zagrożenie.
Shut up, you monster!
Zamknij się, potworze!
What?
Co?
Stop right there!
Stój!
If you attack this human, I will kill you!
Jeśli zaatakujesz tego człowieka, zabiję cię.
Now, wait.
Chwila.
I see.
Już rozumiem.
I understand where you're coming from.
Wiem, o co ci chodzi.
But Mr. Right Hand, you know you can simply move over to me.
Ale możesz się do mnie przenieść.
Move over?
Przenieść?
Relocation should not be possible at this point.
To niemożliwe na tym etapie.
What?
Co?
You still have a lot of learning to do.
Musisz się jeszcze dużo nauczyć.
As you say, relocation from a simple structure
Przeniesienie się z prostej ręki do złożonej głowy nie jest możliwe.
But from an arm to an arm? Easy.
Ale z ręki do ręki? To prościzna.
Well?
No i?
I made a spot especially for you.
Zrobiłem ci miejsce.
Now, do you believe me?
Teraz mi wierzysz?
Now, come over and become my right arm!
Chodź do mnie i bądź moją prawą ręką!
We'll be stronger if we inhabit the same host.
Żyjąc w jednym ciele, będziemy silniejsi.
What's the matter?
Co jest?
Hurry up and kill that human and come over.
Zabij tego człowieka i chodź do mnie.
I'm losing valuable blood.
Tracę cenną krew.
If we manage this body together,
Jeśli razem będziemy operować tym ciałem,
we should be able to live for at least 140 years.
możemy żyć co najmniej 140 lat.
Migi.
Migi.
You try my patience.
Tracę cierpliwość.
But you won't have a choice once I cut off that human's head.
Nie będziesz miał wyjścia, gdy obetnę temu człowiekowi głowę.
Hold on!
Czekaj!
Are you mad?
Oszalałeś?
How dare you?
Jak śmiałeś to zrobić?
My…
Moje…
Migi.
Migi.
Did you save my life?
Ocaliłeś mi życie?
I was simply uncertain as to whether relocation was possible.
Nie byłem pewny, czy mogę się przenieść.
I value only my own life.
Cenię tylko swoje życie.
I am tired now. Going to sleep.
Jestem zmęczony. Idę spać.
My body.
Moje ciało.
My…
Moje…
Migi prioritized my life over that other one.
Migi uznał moje życie za ważniejsze.
Migi may have just wanted to save his own life, but…
Może chciał ocalić swoje życie, ale…
Hey, Migi.
Hej, Migi.
Yummy!
Pychota!
What's with the lack of enthusiasm?
Coś ty taki markotny?
Huh?
Co?
Oh, that's not what I meant.
Nieprawda.
Yummy!
Pycha!
That just sounded forced.
Nie brzmiało to szczerze.
My parents are real uptight right now about me even leaving the house.
Moi rodzice denerwują się, gdy wychodzę z domu.
Huh? Why?
Dlaczego?
Well, because of everything going on,
Przez to wszystko, co się dzieje.
like the Mincemeat Murders.
Przez te morderstwa.
Oh.
Rozumiem.
I'd hate to be turned into mincemeat.
Nie chcę zostać zmielonym mięsem.
Yeah.
No tak.
If Murano ever found out about Migi,
Jeśli Murano dowie się o Migim,
I bet she'd freak out.
na pewno się przestraszy.
Is something wrong?
Coś się stało?
You like animals, right?
Lubisz zwierzęta?
Sure, I do.
Jasne, że tak.
I don't do snakes, though.
Ale nie lubię węży.
Are you okay?
Nic ci nie jest?
Yeah.
Nie.
Let's play in the sandbox!
Pobawmy się w piaskownicy!
Man, so close!
O mały włos!
You suck.
Jesteś do bani.
My turn.
Teraz ja.
You missed.
Spudłowałeś.
That's horrible!
To straszne.
Yeah.
Tak.
Let's go. I don't want to watch.
Chodźmy stąd. Nie chcę na to patrzeć.
What's with him?
Co on robi?
Cut it out, you guys.
Dajcie już spokój, chłopaki.
What?
Co?
Izumi-kun.
Izumi-kun.
It's just a game.
To tylko zabawa.
No one asked you to butt in!
Nie wtrącaj się!
Animals aren't toys!
Zwierzęta to nie są zabawki.
They're alive, just like you.
Żyją, jak wy.
Corny!
Ale frajer!
Are you kidding me?
Mówisz poważnie?
Watch out!
Uważaj!
Want me to eat you?
Mam was zjeść?
Let's go.
Chodźmy.
Okay.
Dobrze.
Just like Migi said,
Jak Migi mówił,
maybe humans are the closest things
może ludziom najbliżej jest
to demons alive.
do demonów.
Izumi-kun.
- Izumi-kun. -Tak?
You are Izumi Shinichi-kun, right?
Jesteś Izumi Shinichi-kun, prawda?
Yeah, of course.
Jasne, że to ja.
Next time, "The Feast."
Następny odcinek: „Uczta”.